so now we have seen that we really want
to have a better predictor but the
question is how we have seen that the
predict taken predictor computes the
next pc
as a function of the current pc by just
incrementing it so the question is if
all we know is the current pc is there
any better function that we can use to
form a better prediction of what's
coming next and the answer is if all you
know is the current pc
then probably you cannot make much of a
better prediction
it would help us
if we knew
is the instruction a branch but we don't
know that we are still fetching the
instruction while we are making the
prediction is this instruction gonna be
taken
as a branch again we have no clue about
that
what is the offset field
of the instruction if this is a branch
this is what will be added to the pc to
form the target address if it's taken
but we don't know that either because we
haven't fetched instruction so really
we don't know for sure anything
that might be really useful in forming
the good prediction so it seems like
it's hopeless but it's not
so what do we know
if we don't know anything for certain
what we do know
is what the current pc is but we also
know something about how that branch at
this pc was behaving in the past and we
can use that because it turns out that
branches tend to behave the same way
over and over again so really that is
what we can use
we don't know for sure what this branch
is going to do
but we can know what it did
the few previous times when it was
executed